PUSHPENDRA CHANDRAVANSHI

Bhopal, MP, India

+91-916-555-6535

pushpendrachandravanshi4@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

As a Front End Developer with 1.5 years of experience, I am skilled in building and maintaining user-friendly and visually appealing websites using a variety of technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, NextJS, MaterialUI, Tailwind CSS, etc. I am a team player and can effectively communicate with both technical and non-technical stakeholders. As a developer, I always stay up-to-date on the latest developments in front end development.

SKILLS

HTML5 CSS Javascript ReactJS Tailwind CSS NextJS
DSA(C++) Python NextJS Figma MaterialUI Arduino

EDUCATION

B. Tech 2020 - 2024

Samrat Ashok Technological Institute, Vidisha

CGPA - 8.2 (Till 5th Semester)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Google Summer Of Code - 2023

(May 2023 - Working)

Score Lab (GraphNet)

- Worked on developing a Javascript graph library GraphNet.
- Gained experience of working on Open Source project.
- Gained experience about web socket connections to render node and edges for graph.

Front-End Developer Intern

(January 2023 - April 2023)

Daphnis Labs

- Gained more experience in using ReactJS and Tailwind CSS.
- Learned React Redux in deep and implemented it.
- Worked closely with backend developer and also gained some experience in it.

Front-End Developer Intern

(April 2022 - August 2022)

ADmyBRAND

- Learned new technologies like NextJS, Tailwind CSS, Figma.
- · Gain experience with API Integration, React redux and designing tools like Figma
- · Gain experience of working in a team at a startup.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Codelab

- A full-stack code playground that can generate HTML, CSS, and Javascript files for any component using Al.
- Users can log in and store their files and access them anytime.
- Deployment codelab766.netlify.app/
- Code github.com/Pushpendra766/codelab

Corganiser

- A web app that can arrange your youtube playlist in the form of a course and avoid distractions.
- Users can add multiple playlists and also add notes to each video for future reference.
- Deployment corganiser.netlify.app/
- Code github.com/Pushpendra766/corganiser-react